Yuan-Yao Lou

Senior Software Engineer and Experienced Network Engineer

| Taipei, Taiwan

| 2015/09 - 2017/06

| Hsinchu, Taiwan

| 2011/09 - 2015/06

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Actively seeking for Software Development Engineer and Backend Engineer full-time job in 2021.

3 years of experience as Software Engineer, specialized in system design and automation and EDA software development. 3 years of experience as Network Engineer and researcher, specialized in network system design and Android OS development.

Publications relate to Fog/Edge computing and Internet of Things (IoT) with 1 journal paper, 2 conference papers, and 1 book chapter.

CONTACT

Taipei City

0916399200

in yylou (Yuan-Yao Lou)

PROGRAMMING

Python

Java

C/C++

Scripting

HTML

CSS

Javascript

SYSTEM & TOOL

Linux

LAMP

Android

Django

MongoDB

MySQL

Git

LANGUAGE

Chinese

English

GRE 325 / 340TOEFL 100 / 120

• Rice University ESL Program

• IEEE ComSoc Winter School

EDUCATION

National Taiwan University
M.S. in Computer Science

• **GPA** 3.93 / 4.30

• Thesis Fog/Edge Computing Virtualization for Low-Latency Wearable Services

• Awards Two-time Outstanding TA Awards, Valedictorian of Graduation Ceremony

• Courses Computer Network, Machine Learning, Application of Big Data System

National Chiao Tung University B.S. in Computer Science

• GPA 3.92 / 4.30

• Project Accelerating HEVC by Adopting GPGPU/CUDA

• Awards Two-time Presidential Awards, MOST Research Project Funding and Awards

• Courses Computer Network Administration, IoT Platforms, Free and Open Source Software

EXPERIENCE

Algorithm and Technology R&D Center, Silicon MotionNew Taipei, TaiwanSupervisor Engineer2020/07 - PresentSenior Engineer2017/12 - 2020/06

- Developed automated software system to boost development efficiency (Python, JSON)
- Devised design tracking system by graph algorithms and visualized profile data (Python, SQL)
- · Enhanced design handoff quality by bridging EDA tools' APIs with data consistency checks

Major Accomplishments:

- Coordinated company's first AI product and 7nm/12nm/16nm projects of mobile devices
- Established programming disciplines (Python) and organized training sessions
- Served as on-campus technical recruiter at National Taiwan University (2018 2019)
- Promoted twice within 24 months to Supervisor

Ministry of Science and Technology
Graduate Researcher and Network Engineer

| Taipei, Taiwan | 2015/09 - 2017/09

- Modified Android Wear OS to enable computation offloading through IoT devices
- Built edge network on Raspberry Pi and developed low-latency applications (Python, Java)
- Deployed web applications to control network operation (Django, MongoDB, RESTful API)

Major Accomplishments:

- Eliminated Android wearable devices' connection and computing limitations
- Demonstrated Fog/Edge network prototype in 5G workshop held by Ministry of Economic
- Published two conference papers (IEEE and ACM) and one book chapter

PUBLICATIONS

Book Chapter

 Yuan-Yao Shih, Ai-Chun Pang, Yuan-Yao Lou, "Chapter 13 -Development of Wearable Services with Edge Devices," Fog and Fogonomics: Challenges and Practices of Fog Computing, Communication, Networking, Strategy, and Economics, 2020

Journal Paper

 Xiaoli Wang, Ming-Jye Sheng, Yuan-Yao Lou, Mung Chiang, "Internet of Things Session Management Over LTE — Balancing Signal Load, Power, and Delay," IEEE Internet of Things Journal, 2015

Conference Paper

- Yuan-Yao Shih, Ai-Chun Pang, Yuan-Yao Lou, Ching-Chih Chuang, Liqiang Zhao, Zhiyuan Ren, "Modularized Service Provisioning at Fog Networks," IEEE Vehicular Technology Society (VTS) Asia Pacific Wireless Communications Symposium (APWCS), 2018
- Hsin-Peng Lin, Yuan-Yao Shih,
 Ai-Chun Pang, Yuan-Yao Lou,
 "A Virtual Local-hub Solution
 with Function Module Sharing
 for Wearable Devices," ACM
 International Conference on
 Modeling, Analysis and
 Simulation of Wireless and
 Mobile Systems (MSWiM),
 2016

National Taiwan University Teaching Assistant - Computer Network

| Taipei, Taiwan | 2016/02 - 2017/01

- Designed IRC chatbot application as assignment for socket programming training (Python, C)
- Improved program's robustness and stimulated creativity by peer testing mechanism
- Lectured TCP/IP protocol and demonstrated network packets tracing in Wireshark

Major Accomplishments:

Received two-time Outstanding TA Awards

Princeton University Research Intern in EDGE Lab

| Princeton, NJ, USA | 2014/07 - 2015/03

- Investigated Fog/Edge computing, LTE, Internet of Things (IoT), and Machine Learning
- Developed tools to analyze network packets and profile Android app (Python, Java)
- · Built probabilistic Markov model with automated simulation and visualized numerical results

Major Accomplishments:

- Proposed LTE mechanism enhancement to support IoT-type network sessions
- Published one journal paper (IEEE IoT Journal)

PROJECTS

Special Healthcare & Social Distance Tracing for COVID-19 Volunteering Project with IoT Eye Inc.

| 2020/10 - Present

- Explored cellular IoT solutions to help disabled people and Autism
- Supported Android system integration with wearable devices SDK (Java, React Native) for social distance and contact tracing tools
- Deployed website and designed web architecture and style (Django, Wagtail, Saleor)

MOOC Platform Course Dropout Prediction Machine Learning Course Project

| 2015/12 - 2016/01

- Acted as team leader to train machine learning models and evaluate datasets
- Achieved 96% of accuracy rate by applying ensemble machine learning with factor analysis
- · Analyzed complexity and pros-cons of machine learning models for model blending

MIT App Inventor 2 - LayerBox Feature Open Source Software Course Project

| 2015/03 - 2015/06

- · Delivered new feature to improve programmability of visual programming environment
- Attended App Inventor Summit at MIT in Boston, MA, the USA as developer in 2013

Accelerating HEVC by Adopting GPGPU/CUDA Engineering Course Project

| 2014/07 - 2015/02

- · Acted as team leader and planned project milestone with programming assignments
- Focused on reducing decoding/encoding time by decomposing HEVC
- Presented project findings in English on weekly engineering project seminar
- Funded and awarded by delivering proposal to Ministry of Science and Technology